[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
We see now how regularization can play a role in logistic regression to find much
نحن نرى الآن كيف يمكن أن يلعب التنظيم دورًا في الانحدار اللوجستي لإيجاد
better fits of data and better assessments of probability.
قيم مطابقة على نحو أفضل من البيانات وتقييمات أفضل للاحتمالية.
Let's finally talk about how we can learn them from data coefficient
لنتحدث أخيرًا حول كيفية معرفتها من معامل البيانات
using gradient ascent.
باستخدام التدرج التصاعدي.
And it's just going to be a very very tiny change on what we did for
وسيكون تغييرًا شديد الصغر على ما قمنا به
learning the coefficients in logistic regression.
لمعرفة المعاملات في الانحدار اللوجستي.
So with a tiny change of code, we now address,
لذا بتغيير بسيط في التعليمات البرمجية، نحن الآن نتناول
alleviate, all those over fitting problems that you had before.
ونخفف جميع مشكلات الإفراط في المطابقة التي واجهتك سابقًا.
So again, same setting as before, Training Data, features, same model.
لذا مرة أخرى، نفس الإعداد السابق، بيانات التدريب، الميزات، نفس النموذج.
Now we have L2 regularized logistic regression or
الآن لدينا الانحدار اللوجستي المنتظم L2
log likelihood is quality metric,
أو يكون لوغاريتم الاحتمال مقياس جودة،
and we're going to talk about ML algorithm to address it to optimize it to get w hat.
وسنتحدث حول لوغاريتم تعلم الآلة لتناوله لتحسينه للحصول على w hat.
We're going to be using the same kind of gradient ascent algorithm that we
سنقوم باستخدام نفس النوع من لوغاريتم التدرج التصاعدي الذي
used before, we'll start from some point and we take these little steps.
استخدمناه من قبل، سنبدأ من نقطة ما ونتخذ هذه الخطوات القليلة.
Go eta steps until we get to our solution w hat, and
نذهب لمعامل η التددريجي حتى نحصل على الحل الخاص بنا Ŵt
the same kind of approach, we're taking the old coefficient,
ونفس النهج، نحن نأخذ المعامل القديم
adding eta times the gradient, and getting the new coefficients w, t plus one.
ونضيف η ضرب التدرج، ونحصل على المعامل الجديد w, t زائد واحد.
And so the only thing that we have to ask ourselves is what is the gradient
وهكذا يكون الأمر الوحيد الذي يتعين أن نطرحه على أنفسنا هو ما القيمة التي
equal to now that we've add this extra regularization term?
يساويها التدرج بعد أن أضفنا الآن مصطلح التنظيم الإضافي هذا؟
So we somehow need
لذا نحن بحاجة إلى حد ما
the gradient of
لتدرج
the regularized
لوغاريتم
log likelihood.
الاحتمال المنتظم.
Let's see what that looks like.
لنر كيف يبدو ذلك.
We've seen that our total quality is the sum of the log likelihood of the data,
لقد رأينا أن الجودة الكلية لدينا هي مجموع لوغاريتم الاحتمال للبيانات،
which a measure of fit, minus lambda times our regularization penalty,
وهو مقياس المطابقة ناقص λ ضرب عقوبة التنظيم خاصتنا،
which is this L2 norm squared.
التي تكون تربيع معيار L2 هذا.
And so what is the derivative of this thing?
وهكذا، ما هو المشتق من هذا؟
This is the thing we need to be able to walk into that hill-climbing direction.
هذا هو ما نحتاج إليه لنتمكن من الاتجاه تصاعديًا.
So the derivative of the sum is the sum of the derivative.
لذا مشتق المجموع هو مجموع المشتق.
So the total derivative is the derivative of the first term, the derivative of
وبالتالي يكون المشتق الكلي هو مشتق المصطلح الأول،
the log-likelihood, which, thankfully, we've seen in the previous module,
مشتق لوغاريتم الاحتمال، الذي، لحسن الحظ، رأيناه في الوحدة السابقة.
minus lambda times the derivative of the quadratic term here.
ناقص λ ضرب مشتق المصطلح التربيعي هنا.
And it is how the derivative of the quadratic term we already covered
وهذه طريقة مشتق المصطلح التربيعي الذي تناولناه بالفعل
in the regression course.
في الدورة التدريبية الخاصة بالانحدار.
But we're going to do a quick review here.
ولكن سنجري مراجعة سريعة هنا.
But as you can see, just a small change to your code before,
ولكن حسبما تري، تغيير صغير فقط على التعليمات البرمجية السابقة خاصتك،
we just have to add this lambda times the derivative of the quadratic term.
حيث يتعين علينا فقط إضافة λ ضرب مشتق المصطلح التربيعي.
So the review,
حسنًا بالنسبة للمراجعة،
the derivative of the log-likelihood is going to be the sum of my data points
سيكون مشتق لوغاريتم الاحتمال، مجموع نقاط البيانات خاصتي
of the difference between the syndicate of whether it's a positive example and
حول الفارق بين رابطة ما إذا كان مثالاً إيجابيًّا
the probability of it being positive weighed by the value of the feature.
واحتمال كونه إيجابيًّا مرجحة بواسطة قيمة الخاصية.
And we talked about last module and
وتحدثنا حول الوحدة الأخيرة
interpreted this piece in quite a bit of detail.
وفسرنا تلك القطعة ببعض من التفصيل.
So what I'm going to go over again, we're going to focus on the second part,
لذا ما سأطرق إليه مرة أخرى، سنركز على الجزء الثاني،
which is the derivative of the L2 penalty.
الذي هو مشتق العقوبة L2.
So in other words, what's the partial derivative with respect to some parameter
وبعبارة أخرى، ما هو المشتق الجزئي بالنسبة إلى متغير ما
wj of w0 squared plus w1 squared plus w2 squared,
wj الخاصة بقيمة w0 تربيع زائد w1 تربيع زائد w2 تربيع.
Plus dot, dot, dot plus wj squared plus dot,
زائد نقطة نقطة، نقطة زائد wj تربيع زائد نقطة،
dot, dot plus wd squared.
نقطة، نقطة زائد wd تربيع.
Now if you look at all of this terms
والآن إذا نظرت إلى كل هذه المصطلحات
w zero squared wr squared all of those don't play any role in the derivative.
w صفر تربيع wr تربيع كل هذه القيم لا تلعب أي دور فيما يتعلق بالمشتق.
The only thing that plays a role is wj squared Now what's the derivative
القيمة الوحيدة التي تلعب دورًا في هذا هي wj تربيع، والآن ما هو مشتق
of 30g squared?
30g تربيع؟
It's just 2wj.
هو 2wj فقط.
So that's always going to change in our code, it's actually 2wj.
فسيتغير هذا دائمًا في التعليمات البرمجية خاصتنا فهو بالفعل 2wj.
So in fact, our total derivative is going to be the same derivative that we've
لذا في الواقع، سيكون المشتق الكلي لدينا نفس المشتق الذي
implemented in the past, mins 2 lambda, Times wj.
وضعناه في الماضي ناقص 2 λ، ضرب wj.
So 2 times the regularization coefficient, the regularization penalty,
وهكذا 2 ضرب معامل التنظيم، عقوبة التنظيم،
the parameter lambda times the magnitude, so times the value of that coefficient.
المتغير λ ضرب المقدار، لذا ضرب قيمة ذلك المعامل.
So let's interpret what this extra term does for us.
حسنًا لنفسر ما يجريه لنا هذا المصطلح الإضافي.
So what does the minus 2 lambda wj do to the derivative?
لذا ما الذي تفعله ناقص 2 λ wj بالنسبة للمشتق؟
So wj is positive, this minus lambda wj is a negative term.
إذن، wj موجية، -λwj هذا عبارة عن مصطلح سالب.
Negative contribution to a derivative which means that it decreases
وهو مساهمة سالبة لمشتق مما يعني أن تقلل
wj because you're going to add some negative term to it.
wj لأنك ستضيف مصطلح سالب إليها.
It was positive we're going to decrease it.
لقد كانت موجبة لذا سنقللها.
So since it was positive and
ونظرًا لأنها موجبة وستقوم
you're decreasing it what happens
بتقليلها، فما يحدث هو أن
is wj becomes closer to 0.
wj تصبح قريبة من 0.
So if the rig is positive you have the negative number and
لذا إذا كانت wj موجبة يكون لديك العدد السالب
becomes less positive closer to 0.
وتصبح موجبة بشكل أقل أقرب إلى 0.
And in fact if lambda's bigger then that thing becomes more negative and
وفي الواقع إذا كانت λ أكبر، فعندئذ يصبح ذلك سالبًا بشكل أكبر
going to 0 faster.
ومتجهًا نحو 0 بشكل أسرع.
That's what happens.
وذلك هو ما يحدث.
And if wj is very positive that the decrement is also larger so
وإذا كانت wj موجبة للغاية بحيث تكون القيمة المقللة أكبر كذلك
it becomes again goes to towards 0 even faster.
لذا تصبح، تتجه مرة أخرى نحو 0 بشكل أسرع حتى.
Now if wj is negative then -2 lambda wj is going to be greater than 0.
الآن إذا كانت wj سالبة، فعندئذ -2 λ wj ستصبح أكبر من 0.
Because lambda is also greater than 0.
لأن λ أكبر من 0 كذلك.
And what impact does that have?
وما التأثير الذي يُحدثه هذا؟
So you're adding something positive so you're increasing
حسنًا، أنت تضيف شيئًا موجبًا، لذلك فأنت تزيد
wj which implies that wj becomes,
wj مما يعني أن wj تصبح
again, closer to 0.
أقرب إلى 0 مرة أخرى.
It was negative, and I posited it numbers with, it goes a little closer to 0.
كانت سالبة وحولت أعدادها إلى موجب بهذا، تتجه بشكل أقرب قليلًا نحو 0.
So this is extremely intuitive, the regularization takes
حسنًا هذا أمر بديهي للغاية، حيث يأخذ التنظيم
positive coefficients and decreases them a little bit, negative coefficients and
المعاملات الموجبة ويقللها بعض الشيء، والمعاملات السالبة
increases them a little bit.
ويزيدها بعض الشيء.
So it tries to push coefficients to 0,
لذا فهو يحاول دفع المعاملات نحو 0،
that was the effect has on the gradient, exactly what you expect.
كان ذلك هو التأثير الذي يُحدثه على التدرج، ما تتوقعه تمامًا.
Finally, this is exactly the code that we described in the last module, so
وأخيرًا، هذه هي التعليمات البرمجية التي وصفناها بالضبط في الوحدة الأخيرة،
learn the coefficients of a logistic regression model.
لذا تعلم معامل نموذج الانحدار اللوجستي.
You start with some, that is equal to 0, or
فأنت تبدأ ببعض القيم التي تساوي صفرًا، أو
some other randomly initiated or some kind of smartly initiated parameters.
البعض الآخر التي تم بدأها بشكل عشوائي أو نوعًا ما من المتغيرات التي بُدئت بشكل ذكي.
And you go, for each iteration you go coefficient by coefficient, you compute
وتنطلق، لكل تكرار تنطلق معامل بمعامل، وتحسب
a partial derivative, which is this really long term here, sum over data points.
المشتق الجزئي، الذي هو المصطلح الطويل للغاية هنا، المجموع على نقاط البيانات.
The feature value times the difference between where there's
قيمة الخاصية ضرب الفرق بين حيثما توجد
a positive data point and the predicted value positive, so called a partial j.
نقطة بيانات موجبة وموجب القيمة المتوقعة، لذا يطلق عليها j جزئي.
And you have the same update, wj(t+1) is wj(t) plus the step size.
ويكون لديك نفس التحديث، wj(t+1)‎ هو wj(t)‎ زائد الحجم اتدريجي.
It multiplies the partial derivative just as before,
فهو يضاعف المشتق الجزئي تمامًا كالسابق.
which is the derivative of the likelihood function With respect to wj.
وهو مشتق دالة الاحتمال بالنسبة إلى wj.
And all you need to change in your code,
وكل ما تحتاج إلى تغييره هو التعليمات البرمجية الخاصة بك،
there's only one little thing to change in the code.
فهناك شيء واحد صغير يتعين تغييره في التعليمات البرمجية.
You have this little thing here which is our only change.
لديك هذا الشيء الصغير هنا وهو التغير الوحيد الذي نجريه.
In other words, take all the code you had before,
بعبارة أخرى، خذ كل التعليمات البرمجية التي كانت لديك من قبل،
put- 2 lambda wj in the computation of the derivative, and
ضع -2 λ wj في عملية حساب المشتق
now you have a solver for L2 regularized logistic regression.
وأصبح لديك الآن آلية حل للانحدار اللوجستي المنتظم L2.
And this is going to help you a tremendous amount in practice.
وسيساعدك هذا على نحو هائل من الناجية العملية.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]